Akhil Bharti

Front-End Developer

Grounded and solution-oriented developer passionate about frontend development with 2+ years of experience building interactive and responsive apps with a passion for improving user experience. Currently working in React and seeking to apply for the position of Front-end Developer and always eager to try new technologies.

akhbharti@gmail.com

7895061630

Bangalore, India

akhilbharti.com 📻

linkedin.com/in/akhil-bharti-b71516100 in

github.com/akhilbharti 👩

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

KaptureCRM 🗷

07/2019 – Present

Benaaluru, Karnataka

- Responsible for developing UI for the large-scale CRM SaaS Software using React and Redux.
- Improved customer work efficiency by revamping UI by 30%.
- Incharge for developing fully customizable Analytical Dashboard module based on RESTful APIs which helped in Reporting, Managing and Analyzing data in Real Time and increased the work efficiency by 41%.

Software Developer

Sunfox Technologies Pvt. Ltd 🛂

01/2018 - 05/2019

Dehradun.Uttrakhana

Achievements/Task

- Assisted in research and study of various ECG filtering techniques and helped in the development and Implementation of various ECG filters in Matlab.
- Built an eCommerce portal to sell company's product online.
- Assisted in developing various module of Spandan Al Programme.
- Developed an Image Cropping Module for the Spandan AI to predict various anomalies in an Ecg.
- I was incharge for developing UI for a doctor-patient web application for the Spandan Ecg Device using React.
- Developed a sales Dashboard in React for managing sales.

Software Developer Intern

Sunfox Technologies Pvt. Ltd

04/2017 - 07/2017

Dehradun, Uttrakhand

Achievements /Tax

- Designed and developed company's user friendly website.
- Submitted weekly various ideas on expanding the features of Spandan ECG Application.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Technology in Information Technology

DIT University, Dehradun

2014 - 2018

SSC

Hilton's School

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript

React

Redux

Webpac

CSS3

Jest

Enzyme

PROJECTS

Kapture CRM (07/2019 - Present)

 Designed frontend architecture. Improved customer's work efficiency with new UI. Built UI components and integrated RESTful APIs. I learned how to build performance-focused UI using React and Redux. Used Jest, Enzyme to test UI components. Designed, Developed UI for Ticketing, Orders, and Dashboards.

Spandan Portable Ecg Device (08/2017 - 05/2019) 🗹

 Spandan is the ever smallest commercial ECG device for the domestic and medical purpose, Designed and developed for monitoring pupose, Spandan is the most precise and accurate ECG device in its clan.

React Video Application 🗷

 Implemented a video search and a player application using YOUTUBE DATA API and Semantic UI framework.

Video Streaming Web Application Using React js and RMTP server <a>™

- Implemented CRUD operation for streaming live video feed with google OAuth in Redux.
- RMTP server was created using node-media-server.
- OBS was used to serve stream to the web application.

React Pokemon Game 🗷

• The project was created in spare time as a revision of the React State.

React Unsplash Image Search

• This project was created to search HD images usingusing unsplash Api in React.

Micromouse- 'An autonomous path finder robot'

 The proposed Arduino project focuses on building an autonomous robot which uses different path finding algorithms to determine the shortest path between a source and a destination in as minimum time as possible was implemented in JAVA.

LANGUAGES

English

•

Hindi